Guide to the Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA) of Durham, NC records, 1894-1992 RL.11616
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Community Outreach, 1965-1988
  - Rape Crisis Center Subject Files, 1966-1988; 2
    - Legal: System Explanation/Diagram, 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Legal: Victim Belief, 1979; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Lesbian: Counseling, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Male Rape; Abuse by Evangelists, 1988; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Male Rape: Characteristics, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Male Rape: Child, 1980; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Male Rape: Dion, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Male Rape: Goyer, 1984; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Male rape: Testemonial, 1981-1986; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Marital Rape: Connecticut, 1981; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Marital Rape: Jensen, 1988; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Marital Rape: Legal Status, 1981; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Marital Rape: North Carolina, 1988; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Marital Rape: NC Legal Definition, 1987; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Marital Rape: Overview, 1984; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Marital Rape: Spero, 1986; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Media: Durham Morning Herald, 1978; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Media: How to Report Rapes, 1983; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Media: Pornography, 1987; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Media: and Rape, 1985-1987; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Media: Rape/Sexual Violence in Films, 1985; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Medical: Abortions, 1971; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Medical: AIDS, 1986-1988; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Medical: Birth Defects, 1986; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Medical: Condoms, 1984; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Medical: Contraception, 1973; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Medical: Divorce, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Medical: Grief "Loss of a Child", n.d.; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Medical: Gynecological Exam, 1971-1985; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Medical: Morning After Pill, 1975; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Medical: Pregnancy, 1962-1987; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Medical: Prenatal Care, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Medical: Psychotherapy, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Medical: Puberty, 1972-1984; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Medical: Rape, 1977; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Medical: STDs, 1969-1986; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Medical: Substance Abuse, 1975-1986; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Myths: Adult, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Myths: Children, 1984; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Myths: Domestic Violence, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Myths: Incest, 1984; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Myths: "Little Rapes", 1974; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Myths: Rape and Perpetuation, 1973; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Monthly Statistical Reports, 1985; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Offenders, 1983-1988; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Paedophiles, 1978; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Pastoral: Policy on Abortion, 1987; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Pornography, 1984-1986; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - PTSD: Burgess, Holstrom, Brady, 1979; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Rape, 1979-1988; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Rape: Campus Crime, 1985-1988; 1 folders (Box 71)
    - Rape: Power/Anger/Sexuality, 1977; 1 folders (Box 72)
    - Rape: Recovery, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 72)
    - Self Defense, 1975-1987; 1 folders (Box 72)
    - Self Protection: Adults, 1972-1988; 1 folders (Box 72)
    - Self Protection: Pre-Puberty, 1979-1986; 1 folders (Box 72)
    - Sexual Harrassment, 1981; 1 folders (Box 72)
    - Sp. Pops: All, 1984; 1 folders (Box 72)
    - Statistics: Adult/Child Assault, 1979-1987; 1 folders (Box 72)
    - Statistics: All Crimes, 1984-1988; 1 folders (Box 72)
    - Statistics: Offenders and Inmates, 1984-1987; 1 folders (Box 72)
    - Rape, 1978-1985; 1 folders (Box 72)
    - Statistics: Victims, 1986-1987; 1 folders (Box 72)
    - Statistics: Violent Crimes, 1982-1987; 1 folders (Box 72)
    - YWCA Rape Crisis Advisory Committee, 1983; 1 folders (Box 72)
      Administrative records for the Rape Crisis Center.
    - YWCA Rape Crisis Advisory Committee, 1984; 1 folders (Box 72)
    - YWCA Rape Crisis Advisory Committee, 1985; 1 folders (Box 72)
    - YWCA Rape Crisis Advisory Committee, 1986; 1 folders (Box 72)
    - YWCA Rape Crisis Advisory Committee, 1987; 1 folders (Box 72)
    - Forms, 1984; 1 folders (Box 72)
    - Internship: SYETP, 1988; 1 folders (Box 72)
    - RCC: Statistics, 1986; 1 folders (Box 72)
    - RCC: Statistics, 1987; 1 folders (Box 72)
    - RCC: Statistics, 1985; 1 folders (Box 72)
    - RCC: Reports, 1985; 1 folders (Box 72)
    - RCC: Reports, 1986-1987; 1 folders (Box 72)
    - RCC: Reports, 1987; 1 folders (Box 73)
    - RCC Programme Goals, 1987; 1 folders (Box 73)
    - RCC: Executive Director's Report, 1987-1988; 1 folders (Box 73)
    - RCC: Monthly Reports, 1988; 1 folders (Box 73)
    - RCC: Evaluation, 1988; 1 folders (Box 73)
    - RCC: Feasibility Study, 1982-1983; 1 folders (Box 73)
    - RCC: Evaluation, 1985; 1 folders (Box 73)
    - RCC: Acomplishments, 1983-1987; 1 folders (Box 73)
    - RCC: Letters Praising the Center, 1986-1987; 1 folders (Box 73)
    - YWCA Salary Scales, 1987; 1 folders (Box 73)
    - YWCA Executive Director Description, 1988; 1 folders (Box 73)
    - RCC: Front Desk Job Description, 1987; 1 folders (Box 73)
    - RCC: YWCA Assistant to Director, 1985; 1 folders (Box 73)
    - RCC: Clinical Consultants, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 73)
    - RCC: Coordinator of Clinical and Volunteer Services, 1 folders (Box 73)
    - YWCA Night Receptionist, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 73)
    - RCC: RCC Director Job Description, 1985-1987; 1 folders (Box 73)
    - RCC: Budget Charge-Backs, 1987; 1 folders (Box 73)
    - RCC: United Way Budget Criteria, 1988; 1 folders (Box 73)
    - RCC: Budget, 1984-1988; 1 folders (Box 73)
    - Grants, 1984-1985; 1 folders (Box 73)
    - Grants, 1987; 1 folders (Box 73)
    - Training Manual for RCC Volunteers Part 1, 1984 (Box 73)
    - Training Manual for RCC Volunteers Part 2, 1984 (Box 74)
    - Training Manual for RCC Volunteers Part 3, 1984 (Box 74)
    - Training Manual for RCC Volunteers Part 4, 1984 (Box 74)
    - Rape: Helping the Female Victim AV, 1986 (Oversize-box 3)
  - Programming and Outreach, 1974-1988; 3
    - Adult Programs, 1985-1987; 1 folders (Box 75)
      The Programming and Outreach subseries consists of the records of various events and programs that the YWCA put on. These include correspondence, flyers and newsletters from other organizations.
    - Alixe Dancer, 1986-1987; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Annual Report '85, 1985-1986; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Art Fair '87, 1985-1987; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Art Festival '87- Registration, 1987; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Arts, 1985-1987; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Arts and Crafts Fair- 1987, 1986-1987; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Arts Fair '87- Logo, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Arts Fair- Performers, 1987; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Arts Festival 1988, 1985-1987; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Arts Festival Paid Registrations, 1986-1988; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - At-Risk Teens Program Emerging Needs, 1983; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Basic Quilting, 1985-1986; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Bicycle, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Black History Month, 1987-1988; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Black and White Women's Dialogue, 1985-1986; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Black Women in Finance 2/10/86, 1986; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Board Stuff, 1986; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Brochure Development, 1985; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Business- All Staff Communication, 1987; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Business-Health Insurance, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Business- Program Committee, 1983-1987; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Camp Saurakee, 1987; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Career Counseling 2/11, 13, 18, 1986; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Career Planning Group for Women, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Change- BWC, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Child Protection Team Manuals, 1986-1987; 1 folders (Box 76)
    - Christmas, 1985; 1 folders (Box 76)
    - Color Analysis, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 76)
    - Committees, 1986-1987; 1 folders (Box 76)
    - Community Education, 1986; 1 folders (Box 76)
    - Community Programs of Interest, 1984-1987; 1 folders (Box 76)
    - Computer Reprints, 1985-1986; 1 folders (Box 76)
    - Contracts with Facilitators (issued by E.D.), 1986; 1 folders (Box 76)
    - Cooking Series: 5/27/86 Mid Eastern, 5/13/86: French & 5/6: Health, 1986; 1 folders (Box 76)
    - Creating/Inventing Ourselves Program, 1985; 1 folders (Box 76)
    - Czerni Memos, 1985-1986; 1 folders (Box 76)
    - Dances, 1986; 1 folders (Box 76)
    - Debbie Wombwell, 1983-1985; 1 folders (Box 76)
    - Diccer, 1985-1986; 1 folders (Box 76)
    - Differently Abled Women, 1986; 1 folders (Box 76)
    - Duke Chil. Classic, 1987; 1 folders (Box 76)
    - Durham Women's Health Co-op, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 76)
    - Education Options – 1, 1983-1988; 1 folders (Box 76)
    - Education Options – 2, 1982-1986; 1 folders (Box 76)
    - Exercise Programs, 1987; 1 folders (Box 76)
    - Fall/Winter 1985 Program Book, 1 folders (Box 77)
    - Fat Woman Fitness, 1986-1987; 1 folders (Box 77)
    - Films- Women + Political, 1986; 1 folders (Box 77)
    - Fourth Wednesday Forums, 1987; 1 folders (Box 77)
    - The Greater Durham Community Foundation, 1 folders (Box 77)
    - Greensboro YWCA, 1984-1985; 1 folders (Box 77)
    - Halloween, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 77)
    - Handbook of Community Resources, 1986; 1 folders (Box 77)
    - Hanukah, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 77)
    - Health, 1986-1987; 1 folders (Box 77)
    - Health and Physical Fitness, 1 folders (Box 77)
    - Hodge-Podge, 1986-1988; 1 folders (Box 77)
    - Ideas, 1985-1986; 1 folders (Box 77)
    - Info & Referral, 1979-1988; 1 folders (Box 77)
    - In Good Taste: Cooking and Eating for Health, 1987; 1 folders (Box 77)
    - Inventory, 1988; 1 folders (Box 77)
    - Joan- Singing, 1981-1986; 1 folders (Box 77)
    - Job Training, 1984-1987; 1 folders (Box 77)
    - Kwanza, 1985; 1 folders (Box 77)
    - League of Women Voters, 1986; 1 folders (Box 77)
    - Legal Rights, 1983-1988; 1 folders (Box 77)
    - Lesbian/Gay, 1986-1987; 1 folders (Box 78)
    - Lesbian and Gay Parenting: 5/27, 1986; 1 folders (Box 78)
    - Lincoln, 1986; 1 folders (Box 78)
    - Local Newsletters, 1986; 1 folders (Box 78)
    - Memberships, 1986; 1 folders (Box 78)
    - Membership Campaign, 1976-1985; 1 folders (Box 78)
    - Mid-Life-Older Women Support Groups, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 78)
    - Miscellaneous, 1985-1986; 1 folders (Box 78)
    - Modern Dance: Janet Perkins, 1985; 1 folders (Box 78)
    - Monthly Reports, 1986-1988; 1 folders (Box 78)
    - The Motherland: African Music and Dance 2/7/86, 1984-1986; 1 folders (Box 78)
    - Names of Individuals (Local Resources), 1 folders (Box 78)
    - Newsletter, 1985-1986; 1 folders (Box 78)
    - The Newsletter, 1985-1986; 1 folders (Box 78)
    - A Night of Gospel 2/5/86, 1985-1986; 1 folders (Box 78)
    - NCARRV (North Carolina Against Religious & Racial Violence), 1985-1986; 1 folders (Box 78)
    - NCOSH: Toby Lippin, 1985-1986; 1 folders (Box 78)
    - N.C. Quilt Project 3/1/86, 1985-1986; 1 folders (Box 78)
    - NOW/NARAL/Coalition for Choice, 1985-1986; 1 folders (Box 78)
    - Older Women, 1984-1986; 1 folders (Box 78)
    - Older Women Series, 1981-1987; 1 folders (Box 78)
    - Open Dialogue Newsletter, 1987; 1 folders (Box 78)
    - Originals 1986 Winter/Spring Prg. Guide, 1985-1986; 1 folders (Box 78)
    - Other Org. Newsletter, 1985-1987; 1 folders (Box 79)
    - Past Programs 11/85-4/86, 1984-1986; 1 folders (Box 79)
    - Peltier Support Committee/ Info on Native Americans, 1985; 1 folders (Box 79)
    - Printing Projects (Newsletter, Program Guide, etc.), 1985-1986; 1 folders (Box 79)
    - Program Corporation of America, 1985; 1 folders (Box 79)
    - Program Development, 1985-1988; 1 folders (Box 79)
    - Project Adventure, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 79)
    - Questionnaire, 1986; 1 folders (Box 79)
    - Racism, 1982; 1 folders (Box 79)
    - Retreat, 1986; 1 folders (Box 79)
    - Second Annual Durham Arts Festival, 1987; 1 folders (Box 79)
    - Senior Games, 1985-1987; 1 folders (Box 79)
    - Skiing, 1986-1987; 1 folders (Box 79)
    - Smoke Cessation, 1987; 1 folders (Box 79)
    - Starting Your Own Business (Finanswer) 2/8/86, 1984-1986; 1 folders (Box 79)
    - Tax, 1986; 1 folders (Box 79)
    - T-Shirts/Printing, 1986; 1 folders (Box 79)
    - Training, 1986; 1 folders (Box 79)
    - Transportation, 1986; 1 folders (Box 79)
    - Walk Club, 1986-1987; 1 folders (Box 80)
    - What's Fair: Pay Equity/Comparable Worth in North Carolina, 1987; 1 folders (Box 80)
    - Women's Arts Fair 1986-1, 1985-1987; 1 folders (Box 80)
    - Women's Arts Fair 1986-2, 1985-1987; 1 folders (Box 80)
    - Women's Center/I&R Information, 1987; 1 folders (Box 80)
    - Women's Centers (Newsletters), 1985-1986; 1 folders (Box 80)
    - Women's Church Service, 1986; 1 folders (Box 80)
    - Women's Commission, 1986-1987; 1 folders (Box 80)
    - Women's Health, 1985-1986; 1 folders (Box 80)
    - Women's Health Series, 1985; 1 folders (Box 80)
    - Women's History Month, 1986-1987; 1 folders (Box 80)
    - Women Reentering the Workforce, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 80)
    - Women's Sports, 1986-1987; 1 folders (Box 80)
    - Women's Yellow Pages, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 80)
    - Working Women Forums, 1987-1988; 1 folders (Box 80)
    - YWCA Ephemera, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 80)
    - Y Teen Talent Show, 1985; 1 folders (Box 80)
    - World Voices of the YWCA Geneva and Widening Circle AV, 1974 (Box 43)
    - Teen Youth Total Machine Sewing AV, 1978 (Box 58)
    - Amazon (Milwaukee), 1974-1976; 1 folders (Box 81)
      The records are organized alphabetically.
      This subseries contains the various periodicals that the YWCA collected and provided as a public resource. The YWCA and the Women's Health Co-op each subscribed to various newsletters and periodicals from national and local organizations with related missions to the YWCA and the Women's Health Co-op. The Women's Health Co-op periodicals were available as a library of sorts available to the public.
    - Amazon: A Midwest Journal for Women (Milwaukee), 1976-1978; 1 folders (Box 81)
  - YWCA Periodicals, 1965-1979; 4
    - Association For the Study of Abortion (ASA): Bibliography and Reprint, 1965-1974; 1 folders (Box 81)
    - Capital Health Systems Agency (CHSA): Newsletter & Open Line, 1977-1978; 1 folders (Box 81)
    - The Challenge, 1979; 1 folders (Box 81)
    - Cold Day in August (Baltimore), 1974-1977; 1 folders (Box 81)
    - Coyote Howls: A Loose Women's Organization, 1977-1978; 1 folders (Box 81)
    - Desperate Living, 1974-1977; 1 folders (Box 82)
    - Distaff, 1973-1974; 1 folders (Box 82)
    - Distaff, 1974-1975; 1 folders (Box 82)
    - Eastern Women's Center News, 1973-1975; 1 folders (Box 82)
    - Equal Rights Monitor, 1976; 1 folders (Box 82)
    - Every Woman, 1970-1971; 1 folders (Box 82)
    - The Examiner, 1976-1978; 1 folders (Box 82)
    - A Feminary, 1974-1976; 2 folders (Box 83)
    - Feminist Caucus of the National Abortion Federation, 1978-1979; 1 folders (Box 83)
    - Feminist Connections, 1976-1978; 1 folders (Box 83)
    - First Contact: The Forum for Primary Care, 1978-1979; 1 folders (Box 83)
    - A Forum for Changing Men (Portland), 1978; 1 folders (Box 83)
    - The Furies, 1972-1973; 1 folders (Box 84)
    - Health-PAC Bulletin: Health Policy Advisory Center, 1970-1971; 1 folders (Box 84)
    - Health Right Issues, 1975; 1 folders (Box 84)
    - Health Right: Women's Health Forum, 1975-1978; 1 folders (Box 84)
    - Hera, 1975-1978; 1 folders (Box 84)
    - It Ain't Me Babe, 1970-1971; 1 folders (Box 85)
    - Lavender Worker, 1974-1975; 1 folders (Box 85)
    - The Leaping Lesbian, 1977-1978; 1 folders (Box 85)
    - The Lesbian Feminist, 1976-1978; 1 folders (Box 85)
    - Lesbian Front, 1975-1977; 1 folders (Box 86)
    - Madness Network News, 1977-1978; 1 folders (Box 86)
    - Maine Freewoman's Harold, 1974-1978; 1 folders (Box 86)
    - Mental Health Law Project: Summary of Activities, 1976-1978; 1 folders (Box 86)
    - Monthly Extract, 1976-1978; 1 folders (Box 86)
    - Mountain Moving, 1976-1977; 1 folders (Box 86)
    - Moving Out: Feminist Literary & Arts Journal, 1971-1975; 1 folders (Box 86)
    - NARAL newsletters, 1979; 1 folders (Box 86)
    - New Carolina Woman, 1970; 1 folders (Box 86)
    - NIAAA Information & Feature Service, 1979; 1 folders (Box 86)
    - Options by Religious Coalition for Abortion Rights, 1975-1978; 1 folders (Box 86)
    - Peace and Freedom, 1974-1976; 1 folders (Box 87)
    - Peace Center Newsletter, 1975-1976; 1 folders (Box 87)
    - Point Blank Times (Houston), 1976-1978; 1 folders (Box 87)
    - Population Reports: Barrier Methods, 1973-1976; 1 folders (Box 87)
    - Population Reports: Family Planning Programs, 1974-1976; 1 folders (Box 87)
    - Population Reports: Indexes, 1974-1976; 1 folders (Box 87)
    - Population Reports: Law and Policy, 1974-1976; 1 folders (Box 87)
    - Population Report: Oral Contraceptives, 1974; 1 folders (Box 87)
    - Population Reports: Pregnancy Termination, 1973; 1 folders (Box 87)
    - Population Report: Prostaglandins, 1973-1976; 1 folders (Box 87)
    - Population Reports: Sterilization, 1973-1976; 1 folders (Box 87)
    - The Second Wave, 1972-1974; 1 folders (Box 87)
    - Sexual Health and Relationships (SHAR), 1978; 1 folders (Box 87)
    - Siecus, 1979; 1 folders (Box 87)
    - Sister, 1973-1978; 1 folders (Box 87)
    - Sister Courage, 1976-1977; 1 folders (Box 88)
    - Southern Feminist Connection, 1975-1976; 1 folders (Box 88)
    - The Spokeswoman, 1974-1979; 1 folders (Box 88)
    - Union W.A.G.E., 1973-1974; 1 folders (Box 88)
    - Up From Under, 1970-1972; 1 folders (Box 88)
    - Washington Area Women's Center Newsletter, 1974; 1 folders (Box 89)
    - What She Wants, 1975-1976; 1 folders (Box 89)
    - What She Wants, 1977-1978; 1 folders (Box 89)
    - The Woman, 1975; 1 folders (Box 89)
    - Womankind, 1971-1973; 1 folders (Box 89)
    - Woman's World, 1971-1972; 1 folders (Box 89)
    - Women's Free Express, 1974; 1 folders (Box 90)
    - Women's Health Services, 1976-1979; 1 folders (Box 90)
    - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom Newsletter, 1974-1977; 1 folders (Box 90)
    - Women's Press, 1976-1978; 1 folders (Box 90)
    - Women's Rights Law Reporter, 1971-1975; 1 folders (Box 90)
    - Womin Energy, 1977-1979; 1 folders (Box 90)